<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Deebul Nair. My Truth</title>
 <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://deebuls.github.io"/>
 <updated>2016-04-15T11:03:54+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://deebuls.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Deebul Nair</name>
   <email>deebuls@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Creativity</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/2016/04/15/Creativity"/>
   <updated>2016-04-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/2016/04/15/Creativity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How to be creative in work? How do break from daily mundane work to be able to
produce creative work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For creativity you need discipline. With the disciplined mind you restrict
yourself inside a small cocoon of work. Inside this cocoon of smaller work we
spend all our time and energy. As we start spending more and more time inside
this smaller region of work we get vexed and frustrated. But after sometime
out of all this frustration we explode and come out like a butterfly coming
out of it coocn from caterpillar and the colors of creativity bossoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Srimati Aruna Sairam Jaya TV 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very useful tip explains another dimension of how every individual can
develop creativity in their fields.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Are some expereices in english missing</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/english,/hindi/2015/10/02/Are-some-experiences-missing-in-english"/>
   <updated>2015-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/english,/hindi/2015/10/02/Are-some-experiences-missing-in-english</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An random thought that “Tujhe pana ke liye itni shiddath kii ..” is not same
as “I did so much hard work to get you” . i.e. “Pana” ~= Get
—–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that there are several expressions which doesnt have an english
translation. Or if some expresssion which translated from our regional
languages to english renders a very funny reciation.
@todo Some examples of funny ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are some very common expressions in our daily life which we have
adopted the english versions even though, the expression it wants to conceive
is not same as the one in the reginonal language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rest this with a simple example :
&amp;gt; Mujhe tumhein &lt;strong&gt;panna&lt;/strong&gt; hain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I need to get you ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are these statements equal. Does get transfer to pana.
Why does the indian version feels good . and why does the english version
feels authoritarian?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the experinces with the words different? what are the thougths in the
mind..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions to explore.. Let me give it a  thought for now .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I put my findings that “get “ ~= “paana” .
Let me proove it with some solid proofs :) .&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sanskrit articles collection</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/sanskrit/indian-sciences/2014/08/10/sanskrit-articles-collection"/>
   <updated>2014-08-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/sanskrit/indian-sciences/2014/08/10/sanskrit-articles-collection</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;articles&quot;&gt;Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ifih.org/TheCaseforSanskritasIndiasNationalLanguage.htm&quot;&gt;The Case for Sanskrit as India’s National Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Eleven Objections To Sanskrit Literary Theory: A Rejoinder ] (http://www.ifih.org/ElevenObjectionsToSanskritLiteraryTheory.htm)
Prof Kapil Kapoor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[ ] ()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>friends and lovely words</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/2014/08/09/friends-and-lovely-words"/>
   <updated>2014-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/2014/08/09/friends-and-lovely-words</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;testimonials&quot;&gt;Testimonials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never knew the meaning of the word until I used Orkut.. Hmmm Orkut old worlds.
What a time scrap book, grapewine, communities and testimonials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we know that our piece of history Orkut is going to shut office this year 
September 2014. So I thought lets gather my memories(The glorifying ones!) for the future .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pushya-francis&quot;&gt;Pushya Francis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;fb-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=604872789634164&amp;amp;set=a.257485364372910.60361.100003343440582&amp;amp;type=1&quot; data-width=&quot;466&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;fb-xfbml-parse-ignore&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=604872789634164&amp;amp;set=a.257485364372910.60361.100003343440582&amp;amp;type=1&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pushya.francis&quot;&gt;Pushya Francis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its a fact that no one can understand any other person, but with Pushya you 
cant even think to try. If we look at our friendship graph for the past 10 years.
It will be most a up and down curve in the begining with gradually the ups and downs spreading wide,
with greater gaps in between. But I am very sure the peaks of all the ups and downs have same heights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not wasting words on her, not because she is worthless but because she is really unexplainable and a person to experience not read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what she thought of me 10 years back (Whenever I read this I always think she loves me )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date : May 3, 2010&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;DEEBUL – thee bull dog!Dats how v used 2 call him. Met dis creative n brainy
lad in my 10th std …seemed v arrogant n unapproachable …bt wen v bcam frnz he was altogether a different guy – v warm ,loving, surprisingly matured yet silly n sweet…since den v hv come a long way now v r gr8 pals who wont spare a single opportunity teasin, fightin n pullin eacthrs leg
sumtimes hes an absolute devil whos sole aim in life is 2 torture othrs n sumtimes hes a darling…bt dats v rare
hes a guy who lives life 2d fullest, knws 2hv fun super lively n v unpredictable.if he can make ur day he can also b responsible 4tsumani type trouble. yet ppl luv him 4 d monster dat he is coz hes a swthrt,a gem of a person &amp;amp; a very rare 2 find kinda frnd.
2gether v had gr8 happening years of fun n adventure n hope it continues…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymous&quot;&gt;Anonymous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Amit wrote this (Hope I am right )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date : Jul 4, 2009&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Deebul is alwys der for people who needs him.They will go back wid a peace of mind and they will always have a smile on their face.i remember, Deebul help us a lot in my final year project and all thx to the great Deebul.
Now anything I say about his talent its gonna be less.
He is a complete all-rounder n..his talents and creativity extends frm Dancing, music,sports,electronics,Linux and many more things.
He is very hardworking n…alwys like to do new things.I alwys respect him for his talent.
He is Multitasker….Everytime that I have seen Deebul he’s always doing atleast two things at a time. Only great people can do that and Deebul is one among them. 
Hhmm…I m nt sure but he is slightly dreamer 1.He keeps dreaming higher and higher.Maybe its something huge for normal people like us.
Deebul is full of emotions..n..its very easy to blackmail Deebul emotionally .
Dude I wish u get everything in life !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymous-1&quot;&gt;Anonymous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date : Jul 2, 2009&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;i know i know..i should be ashamed of myself to have written about this cool ice so late….but atleast I am writing..n I am sure he will be really glad that i finnaly did.I met him first time in our Engineering College. n…I thought a guy like him must b full of attitude but it didn’t took me long to realize that how wrong I was. I came to know that I was quite lucky to have a friend like him.
Hhmm…I remember d traditional day when he had worn White Lungi. ..hahaha….I swear,tht time he were looking typical Mallu.dats why we call him as ‘Anna ‘.
I think u people very well know wat kind of person he actually is ..no hidden layers !He wants something from u he’ll ask for it…no masking it under something or talking indirectly.He is coolest.His intension is always good and never hurt anyone and always tries to bring smile.
One of the greatest qualities of Deebul is that he mostly never says a no to anyone who come to him for help.Whether it is emotional support or financial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jithin-valson-jacob&quot;&gt;Jithin Valson Jacob&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yup, the casonova of Orkut. The one guy who tested and utilized all the features of 
orkut to his best use, no one else than Jithin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets check his thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date : Feb 6, 2007&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here is DEEBUL 4 U……
He is addressed by different names in different areas like REDBUL,ANNA,SWAMI &amp;amp; names of his GF’s etc…..
He is 1 of my gud frndzzzz…I knw him frm my school days..V both hav bcum close frndzzz sinc thn….
A very timepass person….A gud artist…..Always available 4 frndz 4 their help….
But he has changed a lot after his school days…..No1 wil blive hw he ws in school days….
He used 2 b a “BeCHaRa” in his school days…He nvr used to mingle wit girls…But nw….hhmmmmmm…..U can ask his college frnds hw is he nw….nowadays flooded wit girls…He has been linked wit many girls frm his school days…
V frndz loved pulling his legs….He is a born scholar….God knws wen he studies…bcoz he does timepass whol day…..but stil gets gud marks….
But a problem wit him is tht he takes any decision without evn thinking wat wil b its consequences…and he has experienced tis many times…..
Thanx Deebu 4 bein such a gud frnd…GOD bless u dude…Kiddoss 4 our frndship….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymous-2&quot;&gt;Anonymous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date : Jan 30, 2007&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;here i am writin a testi for this person……. ther’s lots to tell abt
him…. wen i first saw him i thought he was vry innocent person but nw i kno
wat is he all abt…. he is vry naughty, funny, cartoon,1 will nvr b sad bein
in his company…. spreads happiness wherevr he is…. any problem i tell him
(althought i dont trust him completely… lol…)n ya vry carin person.
he luvs chicken n also chicks…. a scholar(5th ranker of our colg)…. dont kno wen he studies coz he is always seen playin or roamin abt or watchin movies(a complete movie buff),can watch any kinda movie….. loves dancin a gud dancer, he is calld prabhudeva of our colg….
he can b a gud professor too coz he teaches really well…. a month b4 d exams his classes begin in our colg canteen(his classes a free of cost,but limitd seats… hahaha…)
ther is much more to tell…. will write again som other tym…. luv ya lot n always b d same.
thanx 4 bein such a gr8 frd. (1/30/2007)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testimonials-i-wrote&quot;&gt;Testimonials I wrote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems I am a bit miser here and strange to the unknown.
I have written only 2 testmonials 1 for Janhavi which is a artwork.
and second to Neenad Arul (Really strange) we were not much of a friend, but i always knew that i respected him to the core.
A person of utmost standard of living and thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heres what I wrote for him&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Date : Sep 13, 2008&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;hey baba..hey bogambo..hey drogba..hey dakuu..aee aoo aee aoo aee aooooo
your the coolest daddy i have ever seen oops dude…you amaze us with your wisest reply..with ur rhymic jingles “nazar hati durghatna ghati”…..your way of looking at problems is something i always try to follow..ur dedication to ur friends is wat i admire in you….what i hate is ur hair plz dude if ever u want to cut it ,i will be first to support u..dude u are d coolest saint man!!!!!!! AND I SWEAR MAN EVERYONE WHO KNOWS U THNKS THE SAME ABOUT U?? baki sab jaye bhaad mein»»&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Indian Internet News poster boys</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/entepreneurship/news/2014/08/07/internet-news-poster-boys"/>
   <updated>2014-08-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/entepreneurship/news/2014/08/07/internet-news-poster-boys</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;internet-news&quot;&gt;Internet News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet has changed the way the news has been delivered to the end factors.
Most recent incident of how the Indian goverment has brought a threat to the 
existing Media houses because of the use of social media and internet to connect
directly to the masses caught my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently the technology required for the same is being done by bigger corporate 
houses like SAP, IBM and Salesforce. But I found that there are some inhouse
entrepreneurs in this buisness of bringing 
news to the people through the new media the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-game-changers&quot;&gt;The Game Changers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ajit_Balakrishnan&quot;&gt;Ajit Balakrishnan &lt;/a&gt;
Founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://rediff.com&quot;&gt;rediff.com&lt;/a&gt; A frontrunner in the online news buisness.
The first site to register its name in India. He has seen the complete technology 
born, grow, flourish and boom in front of his eyes. Highly influential person even 
in the government, He is chairman of a government committee tasked with promoting 
research.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B._G._Mahesh&quot;&gt;B. G. Mahesh&lt;/a&gt;
Founder of Mahesh.com and also owner of many online companies most famous &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;OneIndia.in&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Click.in&lt;/a&gt;. Mahesh is a pioneer in Indian Internet. Greatest asset in moving 
the online news to regional languages thus spreading the reach. The company runs 6 
news sites and 1 tech porta and 1 lifesty;e portal all available in 6 regional 
languages. Currently OneIndia.in 
attracts 7.5 million unique visitors in India.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netcore.in/about-netcore/leadership-team/rajesh-jain/&quot;&gt;Rajesh Jain&lt;/a&gt;
The Founder and Managing Director of netCORE Solutions has been one of Mumbai&amp;#8217;s most well-established entrepreneurs.
One of Rajesh&amp;#8217;s early ventures, IndiaWorld Communications, launched in 1995 was 
acquired by Satyam Infoway in November 1999 for US$ 115 million in one of Asia&amp;#8217;s
largest Internet deals. IndiaWorld was the largest collection of India-centric websites,
comprising Samachar (news), Khel (cricket), Khoj (search) and Bawarchi (food).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Data Visualization - current state</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/technology/data%20visualization/2014/08/05/data-visualization"/>
   <updated>2014-08-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/technology/data%20visualization/2014/08/05/data-visualization</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;define&quot;&gt;Define&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-of-technologies&quot;&gt;Reference of technologies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;easy-charts&quot;&gt;Easy Charts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://datawrapper.de/&quot;&gt;DataWrapper&lt;/a&gt;
A beautiful web service that lets you upload your data and quickly generate a chart that you can republish elsewhere or embed on your site. This service was originally intended for journalists, but it is helpful for everyone. DataWrapper displays interactive charts in current browsers and static images for old ones. (Brilliant!) You can also download all the code and run it on your own server instead of using theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flotcharts.org/&quot;&gt;Flot&lt;/a&gt;
A plotting library for jQuery that uses the HTML canvas element and supports older browsers, even all the way back to Internet Explorer 6. It supports limited visual forms (lines, points, bars, areas), but it is easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/chart/&quot;&gt;Google Chart Tools&lt;/a&gt;
Having evolved from their earlier Image Charts API, Google’s Chart Tools can be used to generate several standard chart types, with support for old versions of IE.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://g.raphaeljs.com/&quot;&gt;gRaphaël&lt;/a&gt;
A charting library based on Raphaël (see later in this chapter) that supports older browsers, including IE6. It has more visual flexibility than Flot, and—some might say—it is prettier.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.highcharts.com/&quot;&gt;Highcharts JS&lt;/a&gt;
A JavaScript-based charting library with several predesigned themes and chart types. It uses SVG for modern browsers and falls back on VML for old versions of IE, including IE6 and later. The tool is free only for noncommercial use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://philogb.github.io/jit/&quot;&gt;JavaScript InfoVis Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;
The JIT provides several preset visualization styles for your data. It includes lots of examples, but the documentation is pretty technical. The toolkit is great if you like one of the preset styles, but browser support is unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jqplot.com/&quot;&gt;jqPlot&lt;/a&gt;
A plug-in for charting with jQuery. This supports very simple charts and is great if you are okay with the predefined styles. jqPlot supports IE7 and newer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://omnipotent.net/jquery.sparkline/#s-about&quot;&gt;jQuery Sparklines&lt;/a&gt;
A jQuery plug-in for generating sparklines, typically small bar, line, or area charts used inline with text. Supports most browsers, even back to IE6.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://benpickles.github.io/peity/&quot;&gt;Peity&lt;/a&gt;
A jQuery plug-in for very simple and very tiny bar, line, and pie charts that supports only recent browsers. Did I mention that this makes only very tiny visualizations? +10 cuteness points.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timeline.knightlab.com/&quot;&gt;Timeline.js&lt;/a&gt;
A library specifically for generating interactive timelines. No coding is required; just use the code generator. There is not much room for customization, but hey, timelines are really hard to do well. Timeline.js supports only IE8 and newer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://yuilibrary.com/yui/docs/charts/&quot;&gt;YUI Charts&lt;/a&gt;
The Charts module for the Yahoo! User Interface Library enables creation of simple charts with a goal of wide browser support.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;graph-visualizations&quot;&gt;Graph Visualizations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A “graph” is just data with a networked structure (for example, B is connected to A, and A is connected to C).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arborjs.org/&quot;&gt;Arbor.js&lt;/a&gt;
A library for graph visualization using jQuery. Even if you never use this, you should check out how the documentation is presented as a graph, using the tool itself. (It’s so meta.) It uses the HTML canvas, so it works only in IE9 or current browsers, although some workarounds are available.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sigmajs.org/&quot;&gt;Sigma.js&lt;/a&gt;
A very lightweight library for graph visualization. You have to visit this website, move your mouse over the header graphic, and then play with the demos. Sigma.js is beautiful and fast, and it also uses canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Geomapping&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distinguish between mapping (all visualizations are maps) and geomapping (visualizations that include geographic data, or geodata, such as traditional maps). D3 has a lot of geomapping functionality, but you should know about these other tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kartograph.org/&quot;&gt;Kartograph&lt;/a&gt;
A JavaScript-and-Python combo for gorgeous, entirely vector-based mapping by Gregor Aisch with must-see demos. Please go look at them now. I promise you’ve never seen online maps this beautiful. Kartograph works with IE7 and newer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://leafletjs.com/&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt;
A library for tiled maps, designed for smooth interaction on both desktop and mobile devices. It includes some support for displaying data layers of SVG on top&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of the map tiles. (See Mike’s demo “Using D3 with Leaflet”.) Leaflet works with IE6 (barely) or IE7 (better!) and of course all current browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://modestmaps.com/&quot;&gt;Modest Maps&lt;/a&gt;
The granddaddy of tiled map libraries, Modest Maps has been succeeded by Polymaps, but lots of people still love it, as it is lightweight and works with old versions of IE and other browsers. Modest Maps has been adapted for ActionScript, Processing, Python, PHP, Cinder, openFrameworks…yeah, basically everything. File this under “oldie, but goodie.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://polymaps.org/&quot;&gt;Polymaps&lt;/a&gt;
A library for displaying tiled maps, with layers of data on top of the tiles. Polymaps relies on SVG and thus works best with current browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;almost-from-scratch&quot;&gt;Almost from Scratch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools, like D3, provide methods of drawing visual forms, but without predesigned visual templates. If you enjoy the creative freedom of starting from scratch, you might enjoy these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;[D3 ] (http://d3js.org/)
D3.js is a JavaScript library for manipulating documents based on data. D3 helps you bring data to life using HTML, SVG and CSS. D3’s emphasis on web standards gives you the full capabilities of modern browsers without tying yourself to a proprietary framework, combining powerful visualization components and a data-driven approach to DOM manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://processingjs.org/&quot;&gt;Processing.js&lt;/a&gt;
A native JavaScript implementation of Processing, the fantastic programming language for artists and designers new to programming. Processing is written in Java, so exporting Processing sketches to the Web traditionally involved clunky Java applets. Thanks to Processing.js, regular Processing code can run natively, in the browser. It renders using canvas, so only modern browsers are supported.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://paperjs.org/&quot;&gt;Paper.js&lt;/a&gt;
A framework for rendering vector graphics to canvas. Also, its website is one of the most beautiful on the Internet, and their demos are unbelievable. (Go play with them now.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaeljs.com/&quot;&gt;Raphaël&lt;/a&gt;
Another library for drawing vector graphics, popular due to its friendly syntax and support for older browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-dimensional&quot;&gt;Three-Dimensional&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D3 is not the best at 3D, simply because web browsers are historically two-dimensional beasts. But with increased support for WebGL, there are now more opportunities for 3D web experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.senchalabs.org/philogl/&quot;&gt;PhiloGL&lt;/a&gt;
A WebGL framework specifically for 3D visualization.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mrdoob.github.io/three.js/&quot;&gt;Three.js&lt;/a&gt;
A library for generating any sort of 3D scene you could imagine, produced by Google’s Data Arts team. You could spend all day exploring the mind-blowing demos on their site.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools-built-with-d3&quot;&gt;Tools Built with D3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to use D3 without actually writing any D3 code, you can choose one of the many tools built on top of D3!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://square.github.io/crossfilter/&quot;&gt;Crossfilter&lt;/a&gt;
A library for working with large, multivariate datasets, written primarily by Mike Bostock. This is useful for trying to squeeze your “big data” into a relatively small web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://square.github.io/cubism/&quot;&gt;Cubism&lt;/a&gt;
A D3 plug-in for visualizing time series data, also written by Mike Bostock. (One of my favorite demos.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dashku.com://dashku.com/&quot;&gt;Dashku&lt;/a&gt;
An online tool for data dashboards and widgets updated in real time, by Paul Jensen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dc-js.github.io/dc.js/&quot;&gt;dc.js&lt;/a&gt;
The “dc” is short for dimensional charting, as this library is optimized for exploring large, multidimensional datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nvd3.org/&quot;&gt;NVD3&lt;/a&gt;
Reusable charts with D3. NVD3 offers lots of beautiful examples, with room for visual customizations without requiring as much code as D3 alone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Polychart.js&lt;/a&gt;
More reusable charts, with a range of chart types available. Polychart.js is free only for noncommercial use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Rickshaw&lt;/a&gt;
A toolkit for displaying time series data that is also very customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tributary.io/&quot;&gt;Tributary&lt;/a&gt;
A great tool for experimenting with live coding using D3, by Ian Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;note--the-above-list-is-taken-from-httpchimeralabsoreillycombooks1230000000345ch02html&quot;&gt;Note : The above list is taken from [http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1230000000345/ch02.html]&lt;/h4&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sanskrit(संस्कृत) Non-translatables</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/sanskrit/2014/08/02/Sanskrit-Nontranslatables"/>
   <updated>2014-08-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/sanskrit/2014/08/02/Sanskrit-Nontranslatables</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;On the basis of Shri Rajeev Malhotras book &lt;a href=&quot;www.BeingDifferentBook.com&quot;&gt;Being Different&lt;/a&gt;,
chapter 5: Sanskrit, there are many words in Sanskrit hencefort संस्कृत which cannot be translated in Latin 
languages basically English. So continuing with his efforts this page tries to 
identify and add more such words which should be used as it is, since the english translation
loosess the semantics in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Book &lt;a href=&quot;www.beingdifferentbook.com&quot;&gt;Being Different, An Indian Challenge to Western Universalism&lt;/a&gt; 
examines the differences between the Indian way of thinking to that of the western.
One of the major differences is in the languages used in the both cultures. Which the book critiques as the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;fashionable reductive translations and argues for preserving certain non-translatable words of संस्कृत.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;non-translatable---mantras-by-rajiv-malhotra&quot;&gt;Non Translatable संस्कृत  Mantras by Rajiv Malhotra&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are the main reasons for preserving  संस्कृत as the way it is :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unique-claim-of-&quot;&gt;Unique claim of संस्कृत&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vibrations, not merely meaning; each vibration has a defined effect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One vibration cannot be substituted for another; hence non-translatability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;protects-dharma-from-digestion&quot;&gt;संस्कृत protects dharma from digestion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When fully translated, dharma dissolves as subset of Judeo-Christianity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add certain संस्कृत words into English: potential as poison pills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;संस्कृत influence on pan-Asian Sanskriti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;list-of-non-translatables&quot;&gt;List of Non-Translatables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;संस्कृत Word&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Its Not equal to&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brahman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Brahman comes from root word “brih” means to expand.  The all-expansive ultimate reality that creates all, lives in all and transcends all.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;In Judaism, GOD was seen on Mount Sinai who is creator of universe&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;BRAHMAN is the cosmos and resides in all of us, unrealized as atman&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;In Judaism, GOD was seen on Mount Sinai who is creator of universe.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;BRAHMAN is not authoritative or punitive.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;GOD is authoritative and punishes those who transgress HIS rules and those who do not follow HIS religion.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;ISHWARA, BRAHMAN, DEVTA and BHAGWAN all have different meanings and contexts of use&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;They all cannot be replaced by GOD just like UNCLE does not necessarily means chacha, mama etc .&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soul&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;In dharmic tradition, the true nature of self or Atman is sat-chit-ananda.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;In Christianity, all humans are born as sinners due to original sin by adam&amp;amp;eve. Hence the true self or Soul is sinful.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;The true nature of Atman can be realised with sadhana or adhyatma vidya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Only through Jesus can the Soul attain salvation.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Atman is present in plants and animals.  Hence nature is as sacred as the self.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Soul is NOT PRESENT in plants and animal. In Bible, GOD gave mankind dominion over plants and animals.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Atman reincarnates. Hence the body is cremated once atman has departed.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Soul DOES NOT reincarnate. Hence in Christianity you get only one body that must be preserved till the ‘end of time’.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dharma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Religion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Dharma comes from संस्कृत word ‘dhri’ which means ‘that which upholds’ or ‘that without which nothing can stand’ or ‘‘that which maintains stability and harmony of universe’’.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Religion is worship of divine that is separate from human, has religious institution/authority and governed. Religious rituals are based on events that happened some time in history. Hence all Abrahmic religions i.e., Judaism, Christianity and Islam are history-centric.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Dharma is conduct, duty, justice, morality, virtue, right and much more.  Animals, Plants, Electrons have dharma but no Religion.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;No such explanation for Religion. Also, Religion is only for humans.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Dharma is not LAW as law is authoritative.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Western religion believe GOD’s law must be obeyed and hence non-followers must be converted or punished.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Murthi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;संस्कृत word ‘Murti’ means real, awakened and expressive of divine spirit.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;In Christianity, If an object is revered/respected but not worshipped is termed as ‘ICON’ but if elevated as divine status it is called ‘IDOL’. In Orthodox Christianity, icons/images are KISSED, TOUCHED, REVERED, RESPECTED but ‘technically’ not worshipped.  What Christians revere are ICONS while images, murtis, devotional objects were termed IDOLS and not ICONS.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Prana-Pratishtha’ pooja is the ritual of infusing the Murtis with prana or divine energy. Its only after prana-pratishtha pooja is offered to Murtis.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;No such thing happens with idols.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Visarjan is the ritual of throwing the Murti in holy water to encourage detachment from the Murti ie encourages non-attachment to Murtis.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;No such thing happens with idols&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;As per Aurobindo, it is not the stone but the divine presence/energy in the Murti to which the prayer is offered&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guru or Rishi or Yogi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prophet or Saint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Guru is one who guides individual disciple’s sadhana.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Saint is one who is dead now and church recognized him enjoying the bliss as promised in Christianity.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Yogis and Rishis devote their lives to attain highest level of consciousness.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Prophet is chosen by GOD to communicate with humans.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moksha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salvation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suffereings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yajna&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sacrifice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Devata&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOD or Pagan God&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kundalini or Shakti&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy Spirit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jati or Varna&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;above-document-history&quot;&gt;Above Document history&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Authored by Ajai Singh], {sirfak@gmail.com, February 27, 2014.}
[Edited by Sriram Natarajan], {srinsriram@gmail.com March 2, 2014.}&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ohm Shanthi Oshaana.. Unconventional</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/films/2014/07/19/Om-Shanthi-Oshaana"/>
   <updated>2014-07-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/films/2014/07/19/Om-Shanthi-Oshaana</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ohm Shanthi Oshaana&lt;/em&gt; is one of the rarest Malayalam romantic comedy, the Film industry has seen in the recent years. A rare phenomenon in HERO claded Malayalam film industry, here comes a women woven story!.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://malayalammovietalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/Ohm-Shanthi-Oshaana.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Poster&quot; /&gt;
—–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some movies make a very significant impact, it shakes you from the conventional film watching paradigm.
I would like to present Ohm Shanthi Oshaana 
in this elite list.
:woman:
First and most a female protagonist, could any one imagine malayalam film with such a point of view.
Never in my 10 years of active film watching(exageration included), 
I had the opportunity to watch of a female protagonist script and that too a comedy romantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story telling ..  right from the days from which films existed story telling is an important skill. To maintain the interest of the audience
in each scene and not loosing them even for a frame is what both Jude Anthany Joseph and Midhun Manuel have excelled without doubts.
:claps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story-line&quot;&gt;Story line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is about the female protagonist Pooja played by Nazriya Nazim, events of her life and eventually in her quest for finding her love of the life.
Hmmm seems like a heard story, but just not to forget the female part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pooja and her parents a fresh, friendly parent child relation. Pooja goes to school and is the tomboy creating havoc everywhere from school to church.
Pooja has friends 2 best. In this fun filled place enters .. taadaaa .. HERO .. Giri played by Nivin Pauly . Macho male and pooja is curious .
The next story evolves around pooja discovering Giri. In the quest for Giri many other characters come into picture. Pooja’s cousin and a friend of Giri David Kanjani played by Aju Varghese,
giri’s mother and Annie teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as expected Pooja falls for Giri..:cupid:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Giri has a background and he is not towards pooja who is still 17 and makes it clear to her to concentrate on her studies.. boo:thumbsdown: .. not good .
Now Pooja goes for her higher studies as doctor. Life has moved on she is living a mechanical life but wait she still has  the gift given by Giri.
Hmm so she has not moved on. Here comes Dr. Prasad Varkey .. whistle pood:clap: for Vineeth Srinivasan. A young dashing succesful Doctor and guess what 
he befriends Pooja. They laugh ha ha , they chat , they move around and LOVE:heart:..oops soory  NO &lt;del&gt;LOVE&lt;/del&gt; They dont fall in love, they are friends. She talks to him about her lost love and he supports her 
and asks her to go for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also a interesting character Jacob Tharackan a fun loving Jolly good person meets Pooja. A very apt role by played Lal Jose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now how Pooja with advices from Annie teacher, Dr Prasad and Jacob faces her life the movie unviels itself.
Not to forget the role of Oshana and Ohm Shanti. Its a take away:v:.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;characters&quot;&gt;Characters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nivin Pauly as Giri Madhavan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nazriya Nazim as Pooja Mathew&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vineeth Srinivasan as Dr. Prasad Varkey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aju Varghese as David Kanjani&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Renji Panicker as Dr. Mathew Devasya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manju Sathish as Annie Teacher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Akshaya Premnath as Neethu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oshein Mertil as Dona&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harikrishnan as Yardley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vinaya Prasad as Rachel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vijayaraghavan as Tomichan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lal Jose as Jacob Tharakan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shobha Mohan as Sumithra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nikki Galrani as Thennal K. Warrier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nimisha Suresh as Sreelakshmi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poojitha Ravindran as Julie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parvathy as Principal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nandakishore as Priest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nelson Shooranadu as Constable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-is-the-winner&quot;&gt;Who is the winner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally acclodes to Jude Anthony Joseph for giving such an refreshing story and a movie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extraodinary story telling by and Screenplay by  both Jude and Midhun Manuel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performance by Nazriya, Nivin, Aju , Renji Panicker and not to forget Lal Jose.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Film to put a smile in the face of each audience with a small hint of message of  Ohm Shanti Oshana , peace for all people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me a Film for lifetime to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;fb-root&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;(function(d, s, id) { var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0]; if (d.getElementById(id)) return; js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id; js.src = &quot;//connect.facebook.net/en_US/all.js#xfbml=1&quot;; fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs); }(document, 'script', 'facebook-jssdk'));&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;fb-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ohmshanthioshaana/photos/a.548096945282985.1073741825.548095251949821/598979996861346/?type=1&quot; data-width=&quot;466&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;fb-xfbml-parse-ignore&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ohmshanthioshaana/photos/a.548096945282985.1073741825.548095251949821/598979996861346/?type=1&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ohmshanthioshaana&quot;&gt;Ohm Shanthi Oshaana&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jekyll Introduction</title>
   <link href="http://deebuls.github.io/lessons,%20technology/2011/12/29/jekyll-introduction"/>
   <updated>2011-12-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://deebuls.github.io/lessons,%20technology/2011/12/29/jekyll-introduction</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This Jekyll introduction will outline specifically  what Jekyll is and why you would want to use it.
Directly following the intro we&amp;#8217;ll learn exactly &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; Jekyll does what it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-jekyll&quot;&gt;What is Jekyll?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a parsing engine bundled as a ruby gem used to build static websites from
dynamic components such as templates, partials, liquid code, markdown, etc. Jekyll is known as &amp;#8220;a simple, blog aware, static site generator&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is created with Jekyll. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Sites&quot;&gt;Other Jekyll websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-jekyll-do&quot;&gt;What does Jekyll Do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a ruby gem you install on your local system.
Once there you can call &lt;code&gt;jekyll --server&lt;/code&gt; on a directory and provided that directory
is setup in a way jekyll expects, it will do magic stuff like parse markdown/textile files,
compute categories, tags, permalinks, and construct your pages from layout templates and partials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once parsed, Jekyll stores the result in a self-contained static &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder.
The intention here is that you can serve all contents in this folder statically from a plain static web-server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can think of Jekyll as a normalish dynamic blog but rather than parsing content, templates, and tags
on each request, Jekyll does this once &lt;em&gt;beforehand&lt;/em&gt; and caches the &lt;em&gt;entire website&lt;/em&gt; in a folder for serving statically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jekyll-is-not-blogging-software&quot;&gt;Jekyll is Not Blogging Software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll is a parsing engine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll does not come with any content nor does it have any templates or design elements.
This is a common source of confusion when getting started.
Jekyll does not come with anything you actually use or see on your website - you have to make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-should-i-care&quot;&gt;Why Should I Care?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is very minimalistic and very efficient.
The most important thing to realize about Jekyll is that it creates a static representation of your website requiring only a static web-server.
Traditional dynamic blogs like Wordpress require a database and server-side code.
Heavily trafficked dynamic blogs must employ a caching layer that ultimately performs the same job Jekyll sets out to do; serve static content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore if you like to keep things simple and you prefer the command-line over an admin panel UI then give Jekyll a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developers like Jekyll because we can write content like we write code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to write content in markdown or textile in your favorite text-editor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to write and preview your content via localhost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No internet connection required.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to publish via git.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to host your blog on a static web-server.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to host freely on GitHub Pages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No database required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-jekyll-works&quot;&gt;How Jekyll Works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a complete but concise outline of exactly how Jekyll works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware that core concepts are introduced in rapid succession without code examples.
This information is not intended to specifically teach you how to do anything, rather it
is intended to give you the &lt;em&gt;full picture&lt;/em&gt; relative to what is going on in Jekyll-world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning these core concepts should help you avoid common frustrations and ultimately
help you better understand the code examples contained throughout Jekyll-Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-setup&quot;&gt;Initial Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;/index.html#start-now&quot;&gt;installing jekyll&lt;/a&gt; you&amp;#8217;ll need to format your website directory in a way jekyll expects.
Jekyll-bootstrap conveniently provides the base directory format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-jekyll-application-base-format&quot;&gt;The Jekyll Application Base Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll expects your website directory to be laid out like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.
|-- _config.yml
|-- _includes
|-- _layouts
|   |-- default.html
|   |-- post.html
|-- _posts
|   |-- 2011-10-25-open-source-is-good.markdown
|   |-- 2011-04-26-hello-world.markdown
|-- _site
|-- index.html
|-- assets
    |-- css
        |-- style.css
    |-- javascripts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_config.yml&lt;/strong&gt;
  Stores configuration data.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_includes&lt;/strong&gt;
  This folder is for partial views.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_layouts&lt;/strong&gt;
  This folder is for the main templates your content will be inserted into.
  You can have different layouts for different pages or page sections.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_posts&lt;/strong&gt;
  This folder contains your dynamic content/posts.
  the naming format is required to be &lt;code&gt;@YEAR-MONTH-DATE-title.MARKUP@&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_site&lt;/strong&gt;
  This is where the generated site will be placed once Jekyll is done transforming it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;assets&lt;/strong&gt;
  This folder is not part of the standard jekyll structure.
  The assets folder represents &lt;em&gt;any generic&lt;/em&gt; folder you happen to create in your root directory.
  Directories and files not properly formatted for jekyll will be left untouched for you to serve normally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(read more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Usage&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Usage&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jekyll-configuration&quot;&gt;Jekyll Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll supports various configuration options that are fully outlined here:
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Configuration&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Configuration&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;content-in-jekyll&quot;&gt;Content in Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content in Jekyll is either a post or a page.
These content &amp;#8220;objects&amp;#8221; get inserted into one or more templates to build the final output for its respective static-page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;posts-and-pages&quot;&gt;Posts and Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both posts and pages should be written in markdown, textile, or HTML and may also contain Liquid templating syntax.
Both posts and pages can have meta-data assigned on a per-page basis such as title, url path, as well as arbitrary custom meta-data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-with-posts&quot;&gt;Working With Posts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a Post&lt;/strong&gt;
Posts are created by properly formatting a file and placing it the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting&lt;/strong&gt;
A post must have a valid filename in the form &lt;code&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DATE-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; and be placed in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory.
If the data format is invalid Jekyll will not recognize the file as a post. The date and title are automatically parsed from the filename of the post file.
Additionally, each file must have &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/YAML-Front-Matter&quot;&gt;YAML Front-Matter&lt;/a&gt; prepended to its content.
YAML Front-Matter is a valid YAML syntax specifying meta-data for the given file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order&lt;/strong&gt;
Ordering is an important part of Jekyll but it is hard to specify a custom ordering strategy.
Only reverse chronological and chronological ordering is supported in Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the date is hard-coded into the filename format, to change the order, you must change the dates in the filenames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags&lt;/strong&gt;
Posts can have tags associated with them as part of their meta-data.
Tags may be placed on posts by providing them in the post&amp;#8217;s YAML front matter.
You have access to the post-specific tags in the templates. These tags also get added to the sitewide collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categories&lt;/strong&gt;
Posts may be categorized by providing one or more categories in the YAML front matter.
Categories offer more significance over tags in that they can be reflected in the URL path to the given post.
Note categories in Jekyll work in a specific way.
If you define more than one category you are defining a category hierarchy &amp;#8220;set&amp;#8221;.
Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
title :  Hello World
categories : [lessons, beginner]
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This defines the category hierarchy &amp;#8220;lessons/beginner&amp;#8221;. Note this is &lt;em&gt;one category&lt;/em&gt; node in Jekyll.
You won&amp;#8217;t find &amp;#8220;lessons&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;beginner&amp;#8221; as two separate categories unless you define them elsewhere as singular categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-with-pages&quot;&gt;Working With Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a Page&lt;/strong&gt;
Pages are created by properly formatting a file and placing it anywhere in the root directory or subdirectories that do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; start with an underscore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting&lt;/strong&gt;
In order to register as a Jekyll page the file must contain &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/YAML-Front-Matter&quot;&gt;YAML Front-Matter&lt;/a&gt;.
Registering a page means 1) that Jekyll will process the page and 2) that the page object will be available in the &lt;code&gt;site.pages&lt;/code&gt; array for inclusion into your templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categories and Tags&lt;/strong&gt;
Pages do not compute categories nor tags so defining them will have no effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-Directories&lt;/strong&gt;
If pages are defined in sub-directories, the path to the page will be reflected in the url.
Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.
|-- people
    |-- bob
        |-- essay.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page will be available at &lt;code&gt;http://yourdomain.com/people/bob/essay.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.html&lt;/strong&gt;
You will always want to define the root index.html page as this will display on your root URL.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;404.html&lt;/strong&gt;
Create a root 404.html page and GitHub Pages will serve it as your 404 response.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sitemap.html&lt;/strong&gt;
Generating a sitemap is good practice for SEO.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;about.html&lt;/strong&gt;
A nice about page is easy to do and gives the human perspective to your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;templates-in-jekyll&quot;&gt;Templates in Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Templates are used to contain a page&amp;#8217;s or post&amp;#8217;s content.
All templates have access to a global site object variable: &lt;code&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; as well as a page object variable: &lt;code&gt;page&lt;/code&gt;.
The site variable holds all accessible content and metadata relative to the site.
The page variable holds accessible data for the given page or post being rendered at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Template&lt;/strong&gt;
Templates are created by properly formatting a file and placing it in the &lt;code&gt;_layouts&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting&lt;/strong&gt;
Templates should be coded in HTML and contain YAML Front Matter.
All templates can contain Liquid code to work with your site&amp;#8217;s data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rending Page/Post Content in a Template&lt;/strong&gt;
There is a special variable in all templates named : &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;.
The &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; variable holds the page/post content including any sub-template content previously defined.
Render the content variable wherever you want your main content to be injected into your template:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div id=&quot;sidebar&quot;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div id=&quot;main&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;#123;{content}&amp;#125;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sub-templates&quot;&gt;Sub-Templates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sub-templates are exactly templates with the only difference being they
define another &amp;#8220;root&amp;#8221; layout/template within their YAML Front Matter.
This essentially means a template will render inside of another template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;includes&quot;&gt;Includes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jekyll you can define include files by placing them in the &lt;code&gt;_includes&lt;/code&gt; folder.
Includes are NOT templates, rather they are just code snippets that get included into templates.
In this way, you can treat the code inside includes as if it was native to the parent template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any valid template code may be used in includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-liquid-for-templating&quot;&gt;Using Liquid for Templating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Templating is perhaps the most confusing and frustrating part of Jekyll.
This is mainly due to the fact that Jekyll templates must use the Liquid Templating Language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-liquid&quot;&gt;What is Liquid?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; is a secure templating language developed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://shopify.com&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;.
Liquid is designed for end-users to be able to execute logic within template files
without imposing any security risk on the hosting server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll uses Liquid to generate the post content within the final page layout structure and as the primary interface for working with
your site and post/page data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-do-we-have-to-use-liquid&quot;&gt;Why Do We Have to Use Liquid?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub uses Jekyll to power &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.
GitHub cannot afford to run arbitrary code on their servers so they lock developers down via Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;liquid-is-not-programmer-friendly&quot;&gt;Liquid is Not Programmer-Friendly.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short story is liquid is not real code and its not intended to execute real code.
The point being you can&amp;#8217;t do jackshit in liquid that hasn&amp;#8217;t been allowed explicitly by the implementation.
What&amp;#8217;s more you can only access data-structures that have been explicitly passed to the template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jekyll&amp;#8217;s case it is not possible to alter what is passed to Liquid without hacking the gem or running custom plugins.
Both of which cannot be supported by GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a programmer - this is very frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But rather than look a gift horse in the mouth we are going to
suck it up and view it as an opportunity to work around limitations and adopt client-side solutions when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aside&lt;/strong&gt;
My personal stance is to not invest time trying to hack liquid. It&amp;#8217;s really unnecessary
&lt;em&gt;from a programmer&amp;#8217;s&lt;/em&gt; perspective. That is to say if you have the ability to run custom plugins (i.e. run arbitrary ruby code)
you are better off sticking with ruby. Toward that end I&amp;#8217;ve built &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/plusjade/mustache-with-jekyll&quot;&gt;Mustache-with-Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-assets&quot;&gt;Static Assets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static assets are any file in the root or non-underscored subfolders that are not pages.
That is they have no valid YAML Front Matter and are thus not treated as Jekyll Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static assets should be used for images, css, and javascript files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-jekyll-parses-files&quot;&gt;How Jekyll Parses Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember Jekyll is a processing engine. There are two main types of parsing in Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content parsing.&lt;/strong&gt;
  This is done with textile or markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template parsing.&lt;/strong&gt;
This is done with the liquid templating language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus there are two main types of file formats needed for this parsing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post and Page files.&lt;/strong&gt;
All content in Jekyll is either a post or a page so valid posts and pages are parsed with markdown or textile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template files.&lt;/strong&gt;
  These files go in &lt;code&gt;_layouts&lt;/code&gt; folder and contain your blogs &lt;strong&gt;templates&lt;/strong&gt;. They should be made in HTML with the help of Liquid syntax.
  Since include files are simply injected into templates they are essentially parsed as if they were native to the template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arbitrary files and folders.&lt;/strong&gt;
Files that &lt;em&gt;are not&lt;/em&gt; valid pages are treated as static content and pass through
Jekyll untouched and reside on your blog in the exact structure and format they originally existed in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formatting-files-for-parsing&quot;&gt;Formatting Files for Parsing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve outlined the need for valid formatting using &lt;strong&gt;YAML Front Matter&lt;/strong&gt;.
Templates, posts, and pages all need to provide valid YAML Front Matter even if the Matter is empty.
This is the only way Jekyll knows you want the file processed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YAML Front Matter must be prepended to the top of template/post/page files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: post
category : pages
tags : [how-to, jekyll]
---

... contents ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three hyphens on a new line start the Front-Matter block and three hyphens on a new line end the block.
The data inside the block must be valid YAML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuration parameters for YAML Front-Matter is outlined here:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/YAML-Front-Matter&quot;&gt;A comprehensive explanation of YAML Front Matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;defining-layouts-for-posts-and-templates-parsing&quot;&gt;Defining Layouts for Posts and Templates Parsing.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;layout&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the YAML Front Matter defines the template file for which the given post or template should be injected into.
If a template file specifies its own layout, it is effectively being used as a &lt;code&gt;sub-template.&lt;/code&gt;
That is to say loading a post file into a template file that refers to another template file with work in the way you&amp;#8217;d expect; as a nested sub-template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-jekyll-generates-the-final-static-files&quot;&gt;How Jekyll Generates the Final Static Files.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Jekyll&amp;#8217;s job is to generate a static representation of your website.
The following is an outline of how that&amp;#8217;s done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll collects data.&lt;/strong&gt;
  Jekyll scans the posts directory and collects all posts files as post objects. It then scans the layout assets and collects those and finally scans other directories in search of pages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll computes data.&lt;/strong&gt;
  Jekyll takes these objects, computes metadata (permalinks, tags, categories, titles, dates) from them and constructs one
  big &lt;code&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; object that holds all the posts, pages, layouts, and respective metadata.
  At this stage your site is one big computed ruby object.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll liquifies posts and templates.&lt;/strong&gt;
  Next jekyll loops through each post file and converts (through markdown or textile) and &lt;strong&gt;liquifies&lt;/strong&gt; the post inside of its respective layout(s).
  Once the post is parsed and liquified inside the the proper layout structure, the layout itself is &amp;#8220;liquified&amp;#8221;.
 &lt;strong&gt;Liquification&lt;/strong&gt; is defined as follows: Jekyll initiates a Liquid template, and passes a simpler hash representation of the ruby site object as well as a simpler
  hash representation of the ruby post object. These simplified data structures are what you have access to in the templates.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll generates output.&lt;/strong&gt;
 Finally the liquid templates are &amp;#8220;rendered&amp;#8221;, thereby processing any liquid syntax provided in the templates
 and saving the final, static representation of the file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes.&lt;/strong&gt;
Because Jekyll computes the entire site in one fell swoop, each template is given access to
a global &lt;code&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; hash that contains useful data. It is this data that you&amp;#8217;ll iterate through and format
using the Liquid tags and filters in order to render it onto a given page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, in Jekyll you are an end-user. Your API has only two components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The manner in which you setup your directory.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The liquid syntax and variables passed into the liquid templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the data objects available to you in the templates via Liquid are outlined in the &lt;strong&gt;API Section&lt;/strong&gt; of Jekyll-Bootstrap.
You can also read the original documentation here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Template-Data&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Template-Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this paints a clearer picture of what Jekyll is doing and why it works the way it does.
As noted, our main programming constraint is the fact that our API is limited to what is accessible via Liquid and Liquid only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll-bootstrap is intended to provide helper methods and strategies aimed at making it more intuitive and easier to work with Jekyll =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you&lt;/strong&gt; for reading this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take a look at []()
or jump right into &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;#8217;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>